att.com 2005-06-24

# AT&T: Privacy Policy: Home

  * AT&T's Online Privacy Policy
  * AT&T's Online Privacy Policy: Informed Choice
  * How AT&T Protects Your Privacy Online
  * Additional Privacy Protections for Children Using the Internet
  * Customer Proprietary Network Information (CPNI)

## AT&T's Online Privacy Policy

Protecting privacy is not a new endeavor for AT&T. AT&T has a long-standing tradition of recognizing and protecting the privacy of customers who use its telecommunications networks. The company maintains strict customer information privacy policies and uses state of the art technologies to safeguard customer information and communications from unauthorized intrusions.

AT&T recognizes that the growth of online services, including Internet services, has created additional privacy concerns, particularly for consumers.

Online privacy concerns focus primarily on the protection of "customer identifiable" information which an individual or other customer reasonably expects to be kept private. As the term suggests, "customer identifiable" information is information that, when associated with an individual identifies that individual, for example, a customer's name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address.

Some Internet users may also wish to know who can learn about what they do on the Internet, even when that online behavior is not directly linked to any information that identifies an individual. For example, advertisers may observe whether visitors to a Web site see or respond to online advertising without knowing who those visitors are.

It is common practice and often a necessity for companies, governments, or other organizations to collect customer identifiable information in order to conduct business and offer services. For example, a telecommunications provider may collect customer identifiable information, such as name, address, telephone number, and a variety of other information in the course of billing and providing telephone service to a customer.

Some activities on the Internet follow very familiar patterns. Consumers signing up for an Internet access service, for example, are usually asked to provide name, address, telephone number and credit card and other information that is typical when the consumer orders a product or service. Similarly, business Web sites may ask visitors to supply information about themselves, particularly when information, services or merchandise are requested, but often simply to be able to better target the company's services to the customer's interests and requirements.

Back to Top

## AT&T's Online Privacy Policy: Informed Choice

AT&T has put in place the following Online Privacy Policy. This policy covers AT&T and its subsidiaries, except AT&T Wireless Services (www.attws.com), now a separate company, and Advanced American Telephones (www.telephones.att.com) which licenses the AT&T Brand to sell telephone equipment. AT&T will continue to protect customer information derived from its local, long distance, cable and wireless services consistent with federal laws and with federal regulations issued by the Federal Communications Commission.

Back to Top

## How AT&T Protects Your Privacy Online

**Collection and Use:** AT&T will collect and use customer identifiable information for billing purposes, to provide and change service, to anticipate and resolve problems with your service, or to create and inform you of products and services that better meet your needs. This means that AT&T may use your customer identifiable information, in conjunction with information available from other sources, to market new services to you that we think will be of interest to you, but we will not disclose your customer identifiable information to third parties who want to market products to you.

When you access the Internet, the computers that host Web sites you visit (Web servers) automatically receive some anonymous information. This "usage data" may include a record of which pages a Web browser has visited. AT&T servers receive usage data when customers visit AT&T Web sites, and when AT&T WorldNet members visit other sites as well. AT&T may use usage data to provide advertising about goods and services that may be of interest to AT&T customers, or to provide customized features and services. AT&T will not use information about your activities on the Internet together with any information that identifies you without your consent.

AT&T and its advertisers may use various kinds of software devices to collect information about Internet use. Small files called "cookies" may be attached to your Web browser. These files identify your browser and save information such as passwords so that Web sites can recognize you. You can set your browser to disable cookies, but some AT&T Web sites (and other Web sites) may not work properly if you do this. [More information about cookies](http://care.att.net/bulletins/cookies.html).

In addition, on some Web sites, AT&T and its advertisers may use small bits of code called "one-pixel gifs," or "clear gifs" embedded in some Web pages, to make cookies more effective. AT&T will not associate the information these software devices collect with your name or email address.

AT&T uses advertising companies to deliver ads on some AT&T Web sites. The advertising companies may also receive some anonymous information about ad viewing by Internet users on AT&T Web sites and other Internet sites. This information may be associated with a customer's Web browser, but cannot be associated with a name or e-mail address without the customer's permission. (This means that advertising companies may know where your computer goes on the Internet, but they don't know who you are unless you tell them.) AT&T does not supply customer identifiable information to advertising companies or to individual advertisers or other third parties. If you go to another Web site, including an advertiser's Web site (for example by clicking on an ad), and request information or enter a contest, be aware that you may be authorizing another company, including an advertising company, to use information you supply. Find out more about the advertising companies that deliver ads on AT&T Web sites, read their privacy policies, and choose whether to let them collect information about what you do on the Internet.

**Disclosure:** AT&T will not sell, trade, or disclose to third parties any customer identifiable information derived from the registration for or use of an AT&T online service -- including customer names and addresses -- without the consent of the customer (except as required by subpoena, search warrant, or other legal process or in the case of imminent physical harm to the customer or others). When AT&T uses other agents, contractors or companies to perform services on its behalf, AT&T will ensure that the company protects your customer identifiable information consistent with this Policy. If AT&T includes your name and any other customer identifiable information in a directory that AT&T creates from information we receive as an online service provider, the company will give you the opportunity to have your information excluded from that directory. Business directories that AT&T creates may, however, contain information obtained from other sources.

**Customer Choice:** A customer may choose not to receive direct marketing communications from AT&T in connection with AT&T online services. Upon such choice, AT&T (a) will not contact that customer directly with marketing messages about AT&T online services, and (b) will not use customer identifiable information obtained from that customer's registration for or use of an online service to contact that customer with marketing messages about any AT&T products or services. A customer may choose not to receive such messages by e-mail, by mail, or by telephone.

**Learn more about how to make this choice:**

  * Information for AT&T consumers
  * Information for AT&T business customers

Customer-identifiable information which a visitor volunteers at one of the AT&T Web Sites to order AT&T services other than online services will be protected just as if the information had been provided under more traditional ways of ordering that service.

**Security:** AT&T has implemented technology and security features and strict policy guidelines to safeguard the privacy of your customer identifiable information from unauthorized access or improper use, and we will continue to enhance our security procedures as new technology becomes available.

**E-mail Contents:** The company will not read or disclose to third parties private e-mail communications that are transmitted using AT&T services except as required to operate the service or as otherwise authorized by law.

**Improper Conduct:** AT&T may also use customer identifiable information to investigate and help prevent potentially unlawful activity or activity that threatens the network or otherwise violates the customer agreement for that service.

**Account Information:** AT&T honors requests from customers to review all customer identifiable information maintained in reasonably retrievable form, which currently consists of your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number and/or billing information, and will correct any such information which may be inaccurate. Customers may verify that appropriate corrections have been made.

**Customer Concerns:** If you are a consumer with concerns about the AT&T online privacy policy or its implementation you may contact us at +1 (888) 9-ATT-WEB.

AT&T also participates in the BBB _OnLine_ ® Privacy Program. Further information about this program is available at [www.bbbonline.org](http://www.bbbonline.org/).

**Changes in Practices:** AT&T will keep this Policy current. The company will inform you of any changes that we make.

Back to Top

## Additional Privacy Protections for Children Using the Internet

AT&T joins the industry in recognizing that children, including young teens, may not be able to make informed choices about personal information requested online.

Accordingly, AT&T does not target children or teenagers (younger than eighteen years of age) for collection of information online. AT&T does not solicit or collect customer identifiable information targeted at children and teenagers under eighteen and does not allow anyone else to do so on an AT&T Web site. In addition, the editorial content of AT&T Web sites designed for children will not knowingly promote or link to any third party Web site that collects customer identifiable information unless that Web site publishes a privacy policy that is easily accessible.

In addition, on all of its online services and AT&T Web sites, AT&T will encourage children to seek the consent of their parents before providing any information about themselves or their households to anyone on the Internet.

AT&T encourages parents to take an active role to protect the privacy and security of their children and to prevent the inappropriate use of information about their children. AT&T supports the development of technologies that help parents to control the collection and use of personal information from children who use online services in their households.

Finally, AT&T complies with all Federal laws and regulations, including the [Children's Online Privacy Protection Act](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/edcams/kidzprivacy/index.html) (COPPA), which requires the consent of a parent or guardian for the collection of personally identifiable information from children under 13 without the consent of a parent or guardian.

Back to Top

## Customer Proprietary Network Information (CPNI)

Under federal law you have a right, and AT&T has a duty, to protect the confidentiality of CPNI. AT&T is currently permitted to use CPNI, without further action by you or by AT&T, to offer additional services of the type you already purchase from AT&T. We would like to use your CPNI to offer you new and different communications-related products and services. Before we can do that, AT&T is required to provide this notice and an opportunity for you to deny AT&T's use of your CPNI. Except as required by law, AT&T will not sell, trade or share your CPNI with anyone outside of AT&T other than its duly authorized agents and affiliates.

CPNI is information that relates to the telecommunications services you buy from AT&T, including the types of services, how much you use them, how they are provided and related calling and billing records. CPNI does not include your telephone number, name, and address.

We will not use your CPNI until 33 days after a notice is sent to you. If at any time you would prefer that AT&T not use your CPNI to offer you other communications-related products and services, you only need to call AT&T at +1 (800) 645-6309 from your home phone. If you receive separate bills for additional telephone numbers, you will need to call from each such billed telephone number should you prefer that AT&T not use your CPNI for that telephone number. Any approval or denial of approval, for the use of your CPNI is valid until you affirmatively revoke such approval or denial. Denial of approval will not affect the services that AT&T provides you or the manner in which the services are provided.

Frequently Asked Questions regarding CPNI

Back to Top
